Daiki **MATSUOKA**

December 11, 2021

Contact

Tel +81(80)15258293

daikoshg@gmail.com

Skills

--- Front-end -----

HTML/CSS ■ ■ ■ □ JavaScript ■ ■ □ □

React ■ □ □ □

- Back-end ----

Python ■ ■ ■ □

Django ■ ■ □ □

Ruby ■ ■ □ □

Ruby on Rails ■ □ □ □

---- Others -----

Streamlit • • • •

R ■ ■ □ □

Scikit-learn ■ ■ ■ □

PyTorch ■ □ □ □

C++ = = = = =

profile

As a materials engineer, I worked for several oil & gas plant projects and consulted materials selection from metallurgy & corrosion points of view. In addition, as a member of Data Scientist Workshop, I developed and deployed a first machine-learning model at the company.

When I was a graduate student, I selected as a member of the Vulcanus in Europe program 2018. This program is financed by the European Commission and the Japanese Ministry of Economy, Trade & Industry attended by 20 Japanese students per year.

experience

Materials Engineer & Data Scientist 2020-

JGC Corporation, Yokohama, Japan

- Worked for several oil & gas plant projects as a materials engineer.
 - Keywords: materials selection, corrosion, metallurgy
- Developed and deployed a machine-learning model to predict power rating of tank mixer using Python, Scikit-learn.
- Developed an internal portal site to deploy developed models using Python, Django and RestfulAPI.

Modeling and Simulation Engineer Intern 2018.8-2019.3

Schlumberger Riboud Product Center, Clamart, France

- Developed a physical system model (Modelica) of an electrical flow control valve.
 - Keywords: brushless DC motor, SVPWM (Space Vector Pulse Width Modulation)

education

Languages

French (C1 certified)

English (TOEIC 875)

Interests

Computing

Designing Website

Reading (Philosophy,

Sociology, etc.)

Playing instruments

Travelling abroad

Master of Engineering, major in Mechanical Engineering 2017.4-2020.3

Machine Elements and Tribology Lab., Doshisha University, Kyoto, Japan Advisors: Tomoko Hirayama, Hidetoshi Sakamoto, Takashi Matsuoka

Bachelor of Engineering, major in Mechanical Engineering 2013.4-2017.3

Machine Elements and Tribology Lab., Doshisha University, Kyoto, Japan

Advisors: Tomoko Hirayama, Takashi Matsuoka

certificates

JDLA Deep Learning for GENERAL 2021 #1 2021.3

JDLA (Japan Deep Learning Association)

2020.11 TOEIC L&R 875

IIBC (The Institute for International Business Communication)

DALF (Diplôme Approfondi de Langue Française) C1 2018.6

République française

Daiki **MATSUOKA**

December 11, 2021

Contact

profile

Tel +81(80)15258293 daikoshg@gmail.com

aaaaaaaaaSelected as a member of the Vulcanus in Europe program 2018. model to predict power rating of tank mixer using Python, Scikit-learn.Developed and deployed a machine-learning model to predict power rating of tank mixer using Python, Scikit-learn.

Skills

Curiosity about music, philosophy, data science,

Python **■ ■ ■** □

Scikit-learn

Django

Diango

C++ ■ ■ □ □

HTML5, CSS $\blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \Box$ MS Office $\blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare$

Languages

French (C1 certified) English (TOEIC 875)

Interests

Computing

Designing Website

Reading (Philosophy,

Sociology, etc.)

Travelling abroad

Playing instruments

experience

2020- Materials Engineer & Data Scientist

JGC Corporation, Yokohama, Japan

• Worked for several oil & gas projects as a materials engineer.

Keywords: materials selection, corrosion, metallurgy

 Developed and deployed a machine-learning model to predict power rating of tank mixer using Python, Scikit-learn.

 Developed an internal portal site to deploy developed models using Python, Django, RestfulAPI.

2018.8-2019.3 Modeling and Simulation Engineer Intern

Schlumberger Riboud Product Center, Clamart, France

Developed a physical system model (Modelica) of an electrical flow control valve.

2017.8 Safety Engineer Intern

USJ Co., Ltd., Osaka, Japan

· Conducted risk assessment of large summer events.

Planned for a new seasonal project and evaluated the risks.

2015.8-2015.9 **Structural Engineer Intern**

Caterpillar Japan Ltd., Akashi, Japan

 Designed a structural component of an excavator at Creo (3D CAD) using FEM analysis.

Gave a presentation to employees including CEO in English.

education

2017.4-2020.3 Master of Engineering, major in Mechanical Engineering

Machine Elements and Tribology Lab., Doshisha University, Kyoto, Japan Advisors: Tomoko Hirayama, Hidetoshi Sakamoto, Takashi Matsuoka

2013.4-2017.3 Bachelor of Engineering, major in Mechanical Engineering

Machine Elements and Tribology Lab., Doshisha University, Kyoto, Japan Advisors: Tomoko Hirayama, Takashi Matsuoka

certificates

JDLA Deep Learning for GENERAL 2021 #1

JDLA (Japan Deep Learning Association)

2020.11 TOEIC L&R 875

IIBC (The Institute for International Business Communication)

2018.6 DALF (Diplôme Approfondi de Langue Française) C1

République française

certificates

2021.3	JDLA Deep Learning for GENERAL 2021 #1 JDLA (Japan Deep Learning Association)
2020.11	TOEIC L&R 875 IIBC (The Institute for International Business Communication)
2018.6	DALF (Diplôme Approfondi de Langue Française) C1 République française
2012.2	Eiken Grade 2 Eiken Foundation of Japan
2011.8	Diplôme d'Aptitude Pratique au Français Grade 2 APEF (Association pour la Promotion de l'Enseignement du Français au Japon)